Finding Aid for Patrick Henry Kelley papers, 1910-1924
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Patrick Henry Kelley papers 1910-1924
Kelley, Patrick Henry, 1867-1925.
0.5 linear feet
851703 Aa 2
Lieutenant Governor of Michigan, 1907-1911, and Republican member of the U.S. House of Representatives. Correspondence, newspaper clippings, speeches and scrapbook concerning his political career and private law practice. Correspondents include: Calvin Coolidge, Louis C. Cramton, Oramel B. Fuller, Chase S. Osborn, Arthur J. Tuttle, Arthur H. Vandenberg, and James E. Watson.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of C. Bruce Kelley (donor no. 4951 ) and came to the library in 1970.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Patrick Henry Kelley was US Congressman from Michigan. He was born near Dowagiac, Silver Creek Township, Cass County, Michigan on October 7, 1867. He moved to Berrien County with his parents, who settled in Watervliet in 1875. He graduated from the Valparaiso (Ind.) Normal School in 1887, then taught school at Fair Plain for several years before attending Michigan Normal College in Ypsilanti. He graduated from the law department of the University of Michigan in 1900. After being admitted to the bar, he commenced the practice of law in Lansing, Mich.
Kelley was also politically active. He was a member of the State Board of Education, 1901-1905; State Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1905-1907; and Lieutenant Governor of Michigan ,1907-1911. He was elected as a Republican to the US House of Representatives in 1912, serving five terms, 1913-1923. He did not seek re-nomination, deciding instead to become a candidate for a seat in the Senate. His bid was unsuccessful and thus he returned the practice of law in Lansing, Mich. He died September 11, 1925.
The collection is arranged into three series: Correspondence; U.S. House of Representatives, 1913-1923; and Photographs.
Subjects:
Lawyers--Michigan.; Michigan. Lieutenant Governor.; Michigan--Politics and government--1922-1928.; Republican Party (Mich.); United States--Politics and government--1923-1929.; United States. Congress. House.; Kelley, Patrick Henry, 1867-1925.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Contributors:
Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Cramton, Louis C. (Louis Convers), b. 1875.; Fuller, Oramel B., b. 1858.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860; Tuttle, Arthur J., 1868-1944.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Watson, James E., 1863-1948.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Correspondence
  - 1910-1922 (Box 1)
    (include letter from Chase S. Osborn, 1910)
  - 1923
    (include letters from Louis C. Cramton throughout 1923)
    - January-June 1923 (Box 1)
      (include letters from Chase S. Osborn, June 18 and June 26; also letters from Oramel B. Fuller, June 24 and June 25)
    - July-August 1923 (Box 1)
      (include letter from Arthur Vandenberg, August 15 and August 27; also letter from James E. Watson, August 10)
    - September-October 1923 (Box 1)
      (include letter from Calvin Coolidge, October 19)
    - November-December 1923 (Box 1)
  - 1924 (Box 1)
    (include letters from Oramel B. Fuller, January 5 and January 7; also letter from Arthur J. Tuttle)
- U.S. House of Representatives, 1913-1923
  - Newspaper clippings, 1916-1924 (Box 1)
  - Political miscellanea, 1914-1923 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, 1922 and undated (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook of speeches delivered in the U.S. House of Representatives, 1913-1917 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Portraits of PHK and of associates of PHK (Box 1)